Valentine Michael

Ejigbo, Lagos | 07031215032 | michael.chionye@gmail.com | www.linkedin.com/in/valentine-michael

Profile

A fullstack developer with over 7 years of professional development experience and a track record of successfully developing, managing, and maintaining software applications across various industries, managing teams, and mentoring over 200 budding developers. Experienced in creating and maintaining enterprise-standard applications. Highly proficient in implementing recommended software development practices ensuring the best outcome possible on any project.

Skills & Abilities

Key Strength

DevOps: Git, Linux, Docker, AWS

Front End: HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, TypeScript, ReactJs NextJs, React Query, React testing library

Back End: Node.js, GraphQL, ExpressJs, PHP. Databases: MongoDB, MySQL.

Others

Mobile: React Native.

Experience

Fullstack Engineer | Freelance | september 2018 - present

- · Collaborated on high-priority, highly scalable applications with up to 6,000 users while being costeffective and increasing application load time by 25%.
- · Reduced costs by 17% through implementing cost saving measures such as data archiving, rate limiting and monitoring and optimising resources that heavily task available resources.
- Established automated testing procedures, resulting in heightened reliability and a 50% reduction in production issues.

Tools Used: JavaScript, TypeScript, Git, ReactJS, Redux, React Query, NextJS, PHP, NodeJS, Puppeteer, ExpressJS, MySQL, MongoDB, Docker, and AWS.

Senior Frontend Engineer | Enugu State Tech Hub | july 2023 - february 2024

- · Created generic dashboards for use across 109 government agencies, cutting development time and costs by over 45% by strategically utilising a single code base with an efficient routing system.
- · Conducted regular code reviews and mentored junior developers to enhance team skills and maintain code quality resulting in a 20% reduction in production errors.
- · Implemented industry standard practices to optimise application performance and to ensure high availability, resulting in a seamless user experience and a reduction in page load time.

Tools Used: JavaScript, TypeScript, Git, ReactJS, React Query, NextJS, GraphQL, and Docker

Senior FullStack Engineer | Digital Dreams Ltd | september 2018 - october 2022

- · Mentored over 200 aspiring software developers from novices to professionals.
- Grew customer base and increased company revenue by 25% through interactive promotions, and engaging postings bringing in prospective students to be trained in tech.
- · Planned, organised, and managed all operational activities of one of the company branches including student and staff welfare and creating financial reports

Tools Used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, ReactJS, NodeJS, MySQL, Python, Java and C++

Presales Manager | Mayakorp Nig Ltd | september 2018 - october 2022

- · Performed company-wide system upgrades and troubleshooting to ensure uptime and maximise productivity.
- · Managed the company inventory and regularly performed system diagnostics and maintenance.
- · Planned, organised, and managed all operational activities of one of the company branches including student and staff welfare and creating financial reports

Tools Used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, ReactJS, NodeJS, MySQL, Python, Java and C++

Key Projects

1 – Square Cart

Skills Used: TypeScript, JavaScript ReactJs, React Query, NodeJs, ExpressJs, Unit and Integration test (jest and supertest), MongoDB.

An ecommerce application that allows purchase directly from a social media platform such as TikTok without leaving the platform.

The code base can be found https://github.com/chionye/square-hackathon URL: https://squarecart.netlify.app/

2 - Medlife

Skills Used: TypeScript, JavaScript ReactJs, React Query, NodeJs. An ehealth application that allows patients receive medical help directly from a doctor without ever leaving their homes.

The code base can be found https://github.com/chionye/medlife-frontend URL: https://medlife-frontend-ten.vercel.app/

Education

NNAMDI AZIKIWE UNIVERSITY AWKA, ANAMBRA STATE. B.sc Computer Science July, 2011 - May, 2015

Activities and Interests

Music, art, reading manga and comics, movies, travel